<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Dungeons and Dragons Manager</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="new_player">New Player</string>
    <string name="existing_player">Existing Player</string>
    <string name="dd_Manager">D&amp;D\nManager</string>
    <string name="start">Start</string>
    <string name="proceed">Proceed</string>
    <string name="class_menu">Class Menu</string>
    <string name="race_menu">Race Menu</string>

    <!-- Races -->
    <string name="dwarf">Dwarf</string>
    <string name="elf">Elf</string>
    <string name="halfling">Halfling</string>
    <string name="human">Human</string>
    <string name="dragonborn">Dragonborn</string>
    <string name="gnome">Gnome</string>
    <string name="half_elf">Half-Elf</string>
    <string name="half_orc">Half-Orc</string>
    <string name="tiefling">Teifling</string>

    <!-- Race Description -->
    <string name="dwarf_description">Dwarves are bold, hardy creatures that typically roam in great
        halls carved out of the sides of mountains.  Though they usually are under five feet tall,
        they are so broad and compact they can weigh around the same as a human two feet taller.
        Dwarves can live to be up to 400 years old, which grants them a perspective on the world
        that shorter-lived races lack. Dwarven kingdoms stretch deep beneath the mountains where the
        dwarves mine gems and precious metals, and forge items of wonder.  The chief unit of dwarven
        society is the clan, and dwarves highly value social standing.  To be clanless is the worst
        fate that can befall a dwarf.  Dwarves who take up the adventuring life might be motivated
        by a desire for treasure, or the command or inspiration of a deity.  A dwarf might also seek
        to restore a clan\'s lost honor, or avenge an ancient wrong the clan suffered.</string>
    <string name="elf_description">Elves are a magical people of otherworldly grace, living in the
        world but not entirely part of it. They live in places of ethereal beauty, in the midst of
        ancient forests or in silvery spires glittering with faerie light, where soft music drifts
        through the air and gentle fragrances waft on the breeze. Elves love nature and magic, art
        and artistry, music and poetry, and the good things of the world.</string>
    <string name="halfling_description">The comfort of home are the goals of most halflings’
        lives: a place to settle in peace and quiet, far from marauding monsters and clashing
        armies; a blazing fire and a generous meal; fine drink and fine conversation. Though some
        halflings live out their days in remote agricultural communities, others form nomadic bands
        that travel constantly, lured by the open road and the wide horizon to discover the wonders
        of new lands and peoples. But even these wanderers love peace, food, hearth, and home,
        though home might be a wagon jostling along a dirt road or a raft floating downriver.</string>
    <string name="human_description">In the reckonings of most worlds, humans are the youngest of
        the common races, late to arrive on the world scene and short-lived in comparison to
        dwarves, elves, and dragons. Perhaps it is because of their shorter lives that they strive
        to achieve as much as they can in the years they are given. Or maybe they feel they have
        something to prove to the elder races, and that’s why they build their mighty empires on
        the foundation of conquest and trade. Whatever drives them, humans are the innovators,
        the achievers, and the pioneers of the worlds.</string>
    <string name="dragonborn_description">Born of dragons, as their name proclaims, the dragonborn
        walk proudly through a world that greets them with fearful incomprehension. Shaped by
        draconic gods or the dragons themselves, dragonborn originally hatched from dragon eggs
        as a unique race, combining the best attributes of dragons and humanoids. Som e dragonborn
        are faithful servants to true dragons, others form the ranks of soldiers in great wars,
        and still others find themselves adrift, with no clear calling in life.</string>
    <string name="gnome_description">A constant hum of busy activity pervades the warrens and
        neighborhoods where gnomes form their close- knit communities. Louder sounds punctuate
        the hum: a crunch of grinding gears here, a minor explosion there, a yelp of surprise
        or triumph, and especially bursts of laughter. Gnomes take delight in life, enjoying
        every moment of invention, exploration, investigation, creation, and play.</string>
    <string name="half_elf_description">Walking in two worlds but truly belonging to neither,
        half-elves combine what some say are the best qualities of their elf and human parents:
        human curiosity, inventiveness, and ambition tempered by the refined senses, love of nature,
        and artistic tastes of the elves. Some half-elves live among humans, set apart by their
        emotional and physical differences, watching friends and loved ones age while time barely
        touches them. Others live with the elves, growing restless as they reach adulthood in the
        timeless elven realms, while their peers continue to live as children. Many half-elves,
        unable to fit into either society, choose lives of solitary wandering or join with other
        misfits and outcasts in the adventuring life.</string>
    <string name="half_orc_description">Whether united under the leadership of a mighty warlock or
        having fought to a standstill after years of conflict, orc and human tribes sometimes form
        alliances, joining forces into a larger horde to the terror of civilized lands nearby. When
        these alliances are sealed by marriages, half-orcs are born. Some half-orcs rise to become
        proud chiefs of orc tribes, their human blood giving them an edge over their full-blooded
        orc rivals. Some venture into the world to prove their worth among humans and other more
        civilized races. Many of these become adventurers, achieving greatness for their mighty
        deeds and notoriety for their barbaric customs and savage fury.</string>
    <string name="tiefling_description">To be greeted with stares and whispers, to suffer violence
        and insult on the street, to see mistrust and fear in every eye: this is the lot of the
        tiefling. And to twist the knife, tieflings know that this is because a pact struck
        generations ago infused the essence of Asmodeus—overlord of the Nine Hells—into their
        bloodline. Their appearance and their nature are not their fault but the result of an
        ancient sin, for which they and their children and their children’s children will always
        be held accountable.</string>

    <!-- Classes Descriptions-->
    <string name="barbarian_description">Barbarians are defined by their rage: unbridled, unquenchable, and
        unthinking fury. More than a mere emotion, their anger is the ferocity of a cornered
        predator, the unrelenting assault of a storm, the churning turmoil of the sea. For some,
        their rage springs from a communion with fierce animal spirits. Others draw from a roiling
        reservoir of anger at a world full of pain. For every barbarian, rage is a power that
        fuels not just a battle frenzy but also uncanny reflexes, resilience, and feats of
        strength.</string>
    <string name="bard_description">Whether scholar, skald, or scoundrel, a bard weaves magic through words and
        music to inspire allies, demoralize foes, manipulate minds, create illusions, and even heal
        wounds.</string>
    <string name="cleric_description">Clerics are intermediaries between the mortal world and the distant
        planes of the gods. As varied as the gods they serve, clerics strive to embody the
        handiwork of their deities. No ordinary priest, a cleric is imbued with divine
        magic.</string>
    <string name="druid_description">Whether calling on the elemental forces of nature or emulating the
        creatures of the animal world, druids are an embodiment of nature’s resilience, cunning,
        and fury. They claim no mastery over nature. Instead, they see themselves as extensions
        of nature’s indomitable will.</string>
    <string name="fighter_description">Fighters are perhaps the most diverse class of characters in the worlds
        of Dungeon and Dragons. Questing knights, conquering overlords, royal champions, elite foot
        soldiers, hardened mercenaries, and bandit kings—as fighters, they all share an
        unparalleled mastery with weapons and armor, and a thorough knowledge of the skills of
        combat. And they are well acquainted with death, both meting it out and staring it
        defiantly in the face.</string>
    <string name="monk_description">Monks are united in their ability to magically harness the energy that
        flows in their bodies. Whether channeled as a striking display of combat prowess or a
        subtler focus of defensive ability and speed, this energy infuses all that a monk
        does.</string>
    <string name="paladin_description">Paladins are united by their oaths to stand against the forces of evil.
        Whether sworn before a god’s altar and the witness of a priest, in a sacred glade before
        nature spirits and fey beings, or in a moment of desperation and grief with the dead as
        the only witness, a paladin’s oath is a powerful bond. It is a source of power that turns a
        devout warrior into a blessed champion.</string>
    <string name="ranger_description">Far from the bustle of cities and towns, past the hedges that shelter
        the most distant farms from the terrors of the wild, amid the dense-packed trees of
        trackless forests and across wide and empty plains, rangers keep their unending
        watch.</string>
    <string name="rogue_description">Rogues rely on skill, stealth, and their foes’ vulnerabilities to get the
        upper hand in any situation. They have a knack for finding the solution to just about any
        problem, demonstrating a resourcefulness and versatility that is the cornerstone of any
        successful adventuring party.</string>
    <string name="sorcerer_description">Sorcerers carry a magical birthright conferred upon them by an exotic
        bloodline, some otherworldly influence, or exposure to unknown cosmic forces. One can’t
        study sorcery as one learns a language, any more than one can learn to live a legendary
        life. No one chooses sorcery; the power chooses the sorcerer.</string>
    <string name="warlock_description">Warlocks are seekers of the knowledge that lies hidden in the fabric
        of the multiverse. Through pacts made with mysterious beings of supernatural power,
        warlocks unlock magical effects both subtle and spectacular. Drawing on the ancient
        knowledge of beings such as fey nobles, demons, devils, hags, and alien entities of the
        Far Realm, warlocks piece together arcane secrets to bolster their own power.</string>
    <string name="wizard_description">Wizards are supreme magic-users, defined and united as a class by the
        spells they cast. Drawing on the subtle weave of magic that permeates the cosmos, wizards
        cast spells of explosive fire, arcing lightning, subtle deception, and brute-force mind
        control. Their magic conjures monsters from other planes of existence, glimpses the future,
        or turns slain foes into zombies. Their mightiest spells change one substance into another,
        call meteors down from the sky, or open portals to other worlds.</string>

    <!-- Classes -->
    <string name="barbarian">Barbarian</string>
    <string name="bard">Bard</string>
    <string name="cleric">Cleric</string>
    <string name="druid">Druid</string>
    <string name="fighter">Fighter</string>
    <string name="monk">Monk</string>
    <string name="paladin">Paladin</string>
    <string name="ranger">Ranger</string>
    <string name="rogue">Rogue</string>
    <string name="sorcerer">Sorcerer</string>
    <string name="warlock">Warlock</string>
    <string name="wizard">Wizard</string>

    <string name="background_menu">Background Menu</string>
    <string name="stats">Drag and Drop the Numbers on the Icons to set the Stats</string>

    <string name="new_or_existing_player">New or Existing Player</string>
    <string name="your_character">Your Character</string>
    <string name="done">DONE!</string>
    <string name="one">1</string>
    <string name="two">2</string>
    <string name="raceDescription">Description of Race</string>

    <!-- Stats -->
    <string name="wisdom">Wisdom</string>
    <string name="charisma">Charisma</string>
    <string name="intelligence">Intelligence</string>
    <string name="dexterity">Dexterity</string>
    <string name="constitution">Constitution</string>
    <string name="strength">Strength</string>

    <string name="class_description">Description of Class</string>
    <string name="myClass">Class:</string>
    <string name="race">Race:</string>

    <!-- Backgrounds -->
    <string name="acolyte">Acolyte</string>
    <string name="charlatan">Charlatan</string>
    <string name="criminal">Criminal</string>
    <string name="entertainer">Entertainer</string>
    <string name="folk_hero">Folk Hero</string>
    <string name="guild_artisan">Guild Artisan</string>
    <string name="hermit">Hermit</string>
    <string name="noble">Noble</string>
    <string name="outlander">Outlander</string>
    <string name="sage">Sage</string>
    <string name="sailor">Sailor</string>
    <string name="soldier">Soldier</string>
    <string name="urchin">Urchin</string>

    <!-- Background Descriptions -->
    <string name="acolyte_description">You have spent your life in the service of a temple to a
        specific god or pantheon of gods. You act as an intermediary between the land of the holy
        and the mortal world. Choose a god and work with your game host to determine the nature
        of your service to that god.</string>
    <string name="charlatan_description">You have always had a way with people. You know what makes
        them tick, you can tease out their hearts\' desires after a few minutes of conversation,
        and with a few leading questions you can read them like they were children\'s books. You know
        what people want and you deliver, or rather, you promise to deliver.The bottle of
        pink-colored liquid will surely cure that unseemly rash, this ointment—nothing more than a
        bit of fat with a sprinkle of silver dust—can restore youth and vigor, and there’s a bridge
        in the city that just happens to be for sale.
    </string>
    <string name="criminal_description">You are an experienced criminal with a history of breaking
        the law. You have spent a lot of time among other criminals and still have contacts within
        the criminal underworld. You’re far closer than most people to the world of murder, theft,
        and violence that pervades the underbelly of civilization, and you have survived up to
        this point by flouting the rules and regulations of society.
    </string>
    <string name="entertainer_description">You thrive in front of an audience. You know how to
        entrance them, entertain them, and even inspire them. Your poetics can stir the hearts of
        those who hear you, awakening grief or joy, laughter or anger. Your music raises their
        spirits or captures their sorrow. Your dance steps captivate, your humor cuts to the
        quick. Whatever techniques you use, your art is your life.
    </string>
    <string name="folk_hero_description">You come from a humble social rank, but you are destined
        for so much more. Already the people of your home village regard you as their champion, and
        your destiny calls you to stand against the tyrants and monsters that threaten the common
        folk everywhere.
    </string>
    <string name="guild_artisan_description">You are a member of an artisan’s guild, skilled in a
        particular field and closely associated with other artisans. You are a well-established part
        of the mercantile world, freed by talent and wealth from the constraints of a feudal social
        order. You learned your skills as an apprentice to a master artisan, under the sponsorship
        of your guild, until you became a master in your own right.
    </string>
    <string name="hermit_description">You lived in seclusion—either in a sheltered community such
        as a monastery, or entirely a lone—for a formative part of your life. In your time apart
        from the clamor of society, you found quiet, solitude, and perhaps some of the answers
        you were looking for.
    </string>
    <string name="noble_description">You understand wealth, power, and privilege. You carry a noble
        title, and your family owns land, collects taxes, and wields significant political
        influence. Work with your game host to come up with an appropriate title and determine how
        much authority that title carries. A noble title doesn’t stand on its own—it’s connected to
        an entire family, and whatever title you hold, you will pass it down to your own children.
        Not only do you need to determine your noble title, but you should also work with the
        game host to describe your family and their influence on you.
    </string>
    <string name="outlander_description">You grew up in the wilds, far from civilization and the
        comforts of town and technology. You’ve witnessed the migration of herds larger than
        forests, survived weather more extreme than any city-dweller could comprehend, and enjoyed
        the solitude of being the only thinking creature for miles in any direction. The wilds are
        in your blood, whether you were a nomad, an explorer, a recluse, a hunter-gatherer, or even
        a marauder. Even in places where you don’t know the specific features of the terrain, you
        know the ways of the wild.
    </string>
    <string name="sage_description">You spent years learning the lore of the multiverse. You
        scoured manuscripts, studied scrolls, and listened to the greatest experts on the subjects
        that interest you. Your efforts have made you a master in your fields of study.
    </string>
    <string name="sailor_description">You sailed on a seagoing vessel for years. In that time, you
        faced down mighty storms, monsters of the deep, and those who wanted to sink your craft to
        the bottomless depths. Your first love is the distant line of the horizon, but the time
        has come to try your hand at something new. Discuss with your game host the nature of the
        ship, how famous it was, whether it\'s still sailing, and your duties on it.
    </string>
    <string name="soldier_description">War has been your life for as long as you care to remember.
        You might have been part of a standing national army or a mercenary company, or perhaps a
        member of a local militia who rose to prominence during a recent war. Work with your
        game host to determine which military organization you were a part of, how far through
        its ranks you progressed, and what kind of experiences you had during your military
        career.</string>
    <string name="urchin_description">You grew up on the streets alone, orphaned, and poor. You had
        no one to watch over you or provide for you, so you learned to provide for yourself. You
        fought fiercely over food and kept a constant watch or others who might try to steal from
        you. You slept on rooftops and in alleyways, exposed to the elements.  You begin your
        adventuring career with enough money to live modestly and securely for at least ten days.
        How did you come by that money? What allowed you to break free of your desperate
        circumstances and embark on a better life?</string>

    <string name="zero">0</string>
    <string name="background">Background:</string>
    <string name="background_description">Description of Background</string>
    <string name="d">D</string>
    <string name="ampersand"><![CDATA[&]]></string>
    <string name="manager">Manager</string>
    <string name="dnd"><![CDATA[D&D]]></string>
    <string name="attributes">Attributes</string>
    <string name="skills">Skills:</string>
    <string name="other_Info">Other Information</string>

</resources>
